-= 翻译&校对&ASS特效：baki =-
我们看到的这个
现场画面非常骇人
We're looking at a very disturbing live shot here.
根据警方消息来源
According to police sources,
机场区域内出现了
具有攻击性的感染者
we're dealing with aggressive infected individuals
在航站楼内部
within the airport premises.
即使两个月过去了
Even after two months,
疫情仍然无法控制
the pandemic is unstoppable.
尽管采取各种措施
全国仍持续出现新病例
Despite the efforts, new cases appear nationwide.
感染症状可能在数日内显现
Symptoms can show sometimes within days
甚至几分钟内就会发作
or even minutes.
感染者会变成无法控制的狂暴野兽
People become uncontrollable raging beasts.
他们极其危险
And they're very, very dangerous.
今天世界卫生组织
Today, the,World Health Organization
正式宣布这是全球性大流行病
officially announced that this is a global pandemic.
我们都要完蛋了！
We're all going to die!
这些人是病人
These people are ill.
他们也有权利
They have rights.
你们怎敢称他们为"野兽"？
And how dare you call them "ferals"?
我只想说
I say one thing.
假新闻
Fake news.
机场隔离区已被突破
The airport quarantine has been breached.
当局要求所有居民居家避难
Authorities are asking everyone to stay at home.
此刻不要外出
Do not go out at this point.
这是真实的
This is real.
正在实时发生
This is happening now.
把他们逐个击毙
Gun them down, one by one.
我们看到警方正在撤离现场
We've seen police fleeing the scene
国民警卫队也在后撤
and National Guard soldiers are falling back.
已立即实施宵禁
Curfew has been ordered with immediate effect.
不要试图逃离
Do not try to escape.
就地寻找掩体隐蔽
Stay where you are and hide.
猎鸭弹
Duck shot.
真够劲
So tough.
嚯
Ooh.
嗯
Hmm.
头顶有点稀疏了
Getting a little thin on top.
来点皂液刺激头皮如何？
How about a little soap to stimulate the scalp?
妈妈？
Mom?
民众已不信任当局
The y don't bel ieve that the authorities
有能力控制局势
are capable of controlling the situation.
商店关闭 公共服务停摆
Shops are closed, public services unavailable,
恐慌情绪蔓延...
and panic reigns...
- 在社会中
- in so ciety
而你们却想非法占有...
and now you want to matter for your own unlawfully...
不能直接射杀 他们是人类
We can't just shoot them, they're people.
当你们高谈公民权利时
People protecting their fellow citizens
民众正在保护自己的同胞
while you are preaching about civil rights in both
妈妈？
Mom?
他们根本不算人类
People, they're not even humans.
你他妈疯了吗？
Are you out of your goddamn mind?
事实并非如此 你心知肚明
That is not true and you know it.
我们正在见证国家的崩溃
We're watching the death of the country
而你们只关心这些狗屁倒灶的事
and the only thing that matters to you is all this crap.
抓到你了
Gotcha.
哈哈
Ha ha.
我不能抛下你
I can't leave without you.
亲爱的我知道你很坚强
I know you're strong enough darling.
我一个人做不到
I can't do this alone.
让我和孩子们说
Let me talk to the kids.
孩子们过来
Kids, come here.
爸爸要和你们说话
Your dad wants to talk to you.
嘿 小南瓜
Hey, pumpkin.
爸爸什么时候回家？
When are you coming home, Daddy?
还不确定 宝贝
I don't know, pumpkin.
你要帮助妈妈
You got to help your mom
去凯莉阿姨家暂住
and get yourselves over to Aunt Carrie's.
可我不喜欢凯莉阿姨家
But I don't like Aunt,Carrie's.
我知道
I know.
等我脱困马上就来接你们 好吗？
I'll pick you up as soon as I get out of here. Alright?
好
OK.
别担心
Don't you worry.
看 我戴着幸运手环
You see, I'm wearing my lucky bracelet
此刻能感受到它的魔力
and I can feel its magic right now.
我保证 一切都会好起来的
I promise, everything's going to be just fine.
再见
Bye.
把包给我
Give me your bag.
穿上这个
Get this on.
快走 快走！
Go, go, go, go, go!
快走！
Go, go, go!
跟紧我
Stay close to me.
艾比 艾比
Abby, Abby.
不！
No!
艾比
Abby.
不
No.
好了
All right.
没事了
It's OK.
你现在安全了
You're safe now.
过来
Come here.
嗯
Yeah.
没事的
It's OK.
好了
OK.
现在安全了
You're safe now.
好吗？
OK?
好
OK.
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
捂住耳朵
Go over your ears.
乖
Good.
好了
OK.
带你离开这里
Get you out of here.
静默地带
丧尸静默区
（10年后）
♪ 玛丽漂浮在咸涩的冬水之上 ♪
♪ Mary is floating on the surface of the water ♪
♪ 沿着海岸线的水面 ♪
♪ Of the shore in the salt water winter ♪
♪ 向外港划动双臂 ♪
♪ Take a stroke further out in the harbor ♪
♪ 深吸气却沉入海底 ♪
♪ Take a breath and it turns diver down ♪
♪ 下潜 下潜 潜水者 ♪
♪ Down, diver, down, diver ♪
♪ 继续向下潜游 ♪
♪ Keep swimming down, diver ♪
♪ 涤净所有 让海水冲刷一切 ♪
♪ Get it all out and go wash it all away ♪
♪ 下潜 下潜 潜水者 持续深潜 ♪
♪ Down, diver, down, diver. Keep swimming down, diver ♪
♪ 洗净所有 让浪潮带走一切 ♪
♪ Get it all out and go wash it all away. ♪
♪ 你能洗净吗？ ♪
♪ Can you wash it away? ♪
♪ 请助我洗净 ♪
♪ Help me wash it away ♪
你记得操作要领
You know the drill.
校准准星
Align the sights.
聚焦十字线
Focus on the reticle.
呼吸
Breathe.
把手指放在——
Place the pad of your finger--
记住这个 老头
Remember this, old man.
自大狂
Cocky.
（阿比盖尔 到此一游）
阿比盖尔 我们走
Abigail, let's go.
快过来炫吧
Dinner time.
好了吗？
Finished?
一
One!
只允许一罐
Only, one!
我们有39种适合热带气候的种子
Well, we got 39 seeds that are good for a tropical climate.
剩下的可以去花园城搞到
The rest we can get in Garden City.
我在那儿有门路
I know a place there.
很难想象我们会当农民
It's hard to picture us as farmers.
我打赌我们会怀念冒险的日子
I bet we'll miss the adventure.
我会想念他们
I'll miss them.
再没了
Nothing more.
哦对了
Oh, and by the way,
我打算把大部分时间都花在沙滩上
I plan to spend most of my time sitting on a beach
喝橙汁
sipping orange juice.
我等不及要看海了
I can't wait to see the ocean.
还有两周
Two weeks.
你的人生清单可以划掉这项了
You can cross it off your bucket list.
侦察兵？
A scout?
对
Yeah.
那大部队肯定在附近
So the pack must be nearby.
至少三十个变种人
At least 30 ferals.
收拾装备
Get your gear.
准备转移
We're moving.
嗨 行动啊
Wakey, wakey.
快点
Come on.
我们要出发了
We're leaving.
去你的
Screw you.
我们可以...
We could...
我们可以往北走
we could go up north.
爬上那个旧摩天轮
We could climb up the old ferris wheel.
不 绕路太远了
Nah, it's too big a detour.
好吧呃...
Okay. Um...
我们可以飞过去
We could fly to the island.
我讨厌飞行
I hate flying.
听着 按原计划走行吗？
Look, just stick to the plan, okay?
但如果那不是侦察兵呢？
But what if it wasn't a scout?
只是个落单的变种人
Just a lonely feral.
这附近除了......
There's no one here except--
好了 好了
Okay, okay, okay.
行
Okay.
剩余弹药量？
Ammo?
9毫米还剩31发 5.56口径40发
31 left of the 9mil and 40 of the 5.56s.
我能做到
I can get it.
这次别莽撞
Don't rush this time.
看准时机
Wait for it.
不不不
No, no, no, no, no.
操！说了别冒进
Fuck! I told you not to rush.
是同一群变种人
It's the same pack.
我们离得很近了
We gotta be close.
阿比盖尔 搜车
Abigail, search the car.
阿比盖尔 走了
Abigail, let's go.
这里
Here.
对不住了伙计
I'm sorry, pal.
子弹不能浪费
We can't waste any bullets.
靴子不错
Nice boots.
能给我吗？
May I have 'em?
啊！
Ahh!
特雷弗 你在哪？完毕
Trevor, where are you, mate? Over.
收拾有用的 快走
Pack what's useful. Let's go.
如果够快的话
If we're fast enough,
我们能赶到山脊
we can make it to the ridge.
变种人就发现不了我们
And the pack might not see us.
但他们会发现那些人
But they'll see them.
不关我们的事
None of our business.
得警告他们
We gotta warn them.
你在哪？说话啊？
Where are you, man? Hey?
嘿 别回应
Hey, don't answer.
动动脑子
Think a little.
他们到这儿会先问什么？
What'll be their first question when they get here?
肯定会问"其他人什么时候到？"
They'll ask, when are the others coming?
阿比盖尔！
Abigail!
喂！
Hey!
阿比盖尔！
Abigail!
你好
Hello!
这他妈怎么回事？
What the hell happened here?
你们同伴被袭击了
Your friends have been attacked.
放下武器举起手来
Drop your weapons and get your hands up.
我说放下武器
I said drop your weapons
举起你他妈的手！
and get your fucking hands up.
好好好 冷静点行吗
All right, man. Take it fucking easy, okay.
检查
Check it.
别怕 我们不想伤害你们
It's okay. We don't want to hurt you.
闭嘴！
Shut up!
我有种不祥的预感
I've got a bad feeling about this.
她只是个孩子
She's just a kid.
那个大块头让我不安
I don't like the look of the big guy.
知道我们最恨什么人吗？
Yeah, you know who we hate the most?
掠夺者
Looters.
我们会像对待其他垃圾一样
We're gonna do the same thing to you
打断你们的腿
that we do to everyone of you scumbags.
抢光你们的东西
We're gonna rip you off, break your legs,
让你们在这烂掉
and leave you here to fucking rot.
你们误会了
You misunderstand.
误会你妈个头
Oh, we do, you little bitch.
嘿！嘿！嘿！
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
别冲动 放下枪
Don't do it. Put it down.
放下
Put it down.
别这样
Don't do this.
冷静点老兄
Take it easy, man.
放开他
Put him down.
别激动
Take it easy.
把枪放下
Put your guns down.
我们不想伤害你们
We don't mean to hurt you.
梅根 回车里！
Megan, get back in the car!
我们只是想提醒你们
Look, we just wanted to warn you.
提醒什么？
Warn us about what?
变种人要来了 必须马上撤离
The ferals. We got to get out of here.
回车上去 快走
Back to the cars. Let go.
操！
Fuck!
妈的！
弹药量
Ammo.
9毫米剩16发 5.56还有37发
Uh, 16 of the 9mil and 37 of 5.56's.
该死 几乎全丢了
Dammit, we lost nearly everything.
你们到底怎么想的
What the hell were you thinking,
这种状态还敢上路？
traveling in that condition?
我们耗尽了一切物资
所以不得不离开
We ran out of everything so we had to leave.
但能去哪呢？
But where to?
往东北方向 去河边的聚居地
一个船镇
Northeast, to a colony on a riverside, a boat town.
你怀孕多久了？
How far along are you?
第三十五周了
It's the 35th week.
那意味着什么？
What does that mean?
意味着她快生了
It means she's close.
那你们呢？
What about you?
你们要去哪里？
Where you going?
绝对不会去东北
Definitely not Northeast.
为什么？
Why not?
我们见过好几个聚居地
We've been to several colonies
哪儿的情况都如出一辙
and we've seen the same everywhere.
什么情况？
Same what?
混乱无序
Same chaos.
该死！
Dammit!
打开引擎盖
Pop the hood.
也许我能修好
Maybe I can fix it.
散热器完蛋了
Radiator's shot.
我们没有备用零件
We have no spare parts.
你他妈是谁 极客小队吗？
The fuck are you, the geek squad?
算是吧
Yeah.
顺便说下 我叫戴维
I'm David, by the way.
阿比盖尔
Abigail.
那个脾气暴躁的家伙是卡西乌斯
And the grumpy guy is Cassius.
这是梅甘
This is Megan.
你好
Hi.
那么现在怎么办？
So, now what?
拿上你们的东西
Get your stuff.
我们离开这里
We're leaving.
别管了 不值得带
Just leave it, not worth it.
我们应该联系那个聚居地
We should contact the colony.
告诉他们我们要过去
Let them know that we're coming.
看起来没问题
Looks fine.
好 五分钟后出发
Okay, five minutes.
我们得找个过夜的地方
We need to find a shelter for the night.
找栋隐蔽点的建筑
A less exposed building.
她撑不了多久了
She won't hold out for long.
那边是旧小学
That's the old elementary school.
杰克逊家的房子就在旁边
And the Jackson house is there.
可以凑合过夜
That'll do for the night.
我们扎营吧
Let's hit camp.
你们确定不吃点吗？
You sure you don't want any?
谢谢 但我们只吃自己猎到的肉
Thanks, but we only eat meat that we hunted
怕有病毒感染
because of the infection.
呃 我们想感谢你们的帮助
Um, we'd like to thank you for helping us.
简直不敢想象如果你们没出现
Can't imagine what would have happened
会发生什么
if you hadn't come.
我敢想
I can.
跟我说说你们原来的住处
Tell me about the place you lived.
那里怎么样？
What was it like?
就是个普通农场
It was just an ordinary farm.
远离尘嚣
Far from everything.
最多时有四十人 但后来...
There were times when it was 40 of us, but then...
后来死神降临了
But then the Grim Reaper came.
那个聚居地呢？
And the colony?
你们了解多少？
What do you know about it?
我们用无线电联系过
We talked to them on the radio
他们有充足的水和食物
and they have plenty of water and food
甚至还有医生
and they even have doctors.
他们把几艘沉船拼在一起
They pulled a couple of shipwrecks together.
现在有上百人住在水上
Now over 100 people live on the water.
有多远？
How far is it?
大约一周路程
It's about a week's travel.
风险很大
It's risky.
但我们投票表决 多数人决定要去
But we voted and the majority decided to go.
因为留下也是死路
Because we couldn't stay.
变种人杀了我们很多人
You know, the ferals killed so many.
上次袭击后 我们不得不烧掉
After the last attack, we had to burn down
整片麦田来阻止他们
a whole wheat field just to stop them.
几乎什么都不剩了
We had almost nothing left.
船镇是唯一安全的地方
The boat town is the only safe place.
你们呢？
And you?
你们怎么活下来的？
How did you survive?
因为我们从不停留
Because we never stopped.
而且卡西乌斯教会了我一切
And Cassius taught me everything.
狩猎、生存、
To hunt, to survive,
还有最重要的道理
and even the most important thing.
独行更安全
We're better off alone.
你只能依靠自己
You can only count on yourself.
别告诉我你们打算这样
Tell me this is not your plan.
永远像游魂般四处漂泊
To just wander around until the end of time.
不 我们要去西海岸
No, we are headed to the west coast.
然后乘船去海岛
Then to the islands by boat.
好吧那么...
Okay. So...
这里是你朋友遇害的地方
This is where your friends were killed.
这是我们现在的位置
And this is where we are now.
我不建议走50号旧公路
I wouldn't recommend the old route 50.
但如果从这里向北走
But if you had North here,
可以出城
you get out of the city.
这边的55号公路
And the 55 here,
通往河边
takes you to the river.
呃...
Uhm...
我们想结伴同行？
We thought we'd go together?
你们要和我们一起走？
That you'd come with us?
对
Yeah.
不
Nah.
这主意不好
That's not a good idea.
为什么不好？
Well, why not?
因为...
Well...
因为我们是这片区域仅存的活人
Because we're the only survivors in the area.
等那群畜生吃完你朋友的尸体
And when the pack finishes the feast from your friends,
随时可能想起我们的存在
which can happen any minute now, they'll remember us.
所以我要在他们想起之前
逃得越远越好
So, I wanna be as far away as possible when that happens.
明白吗？
Got it?
我以为我们已经够远了
I thought we were far enough.
够远？
Far enough?
根本没有"够远"这回事 亲爱的
Far enough don't exist, sweetheart.
所以我们不结伴
That's why we don't join.
这就是生存法则
That's the trick.
建议你们也这样做
I suggest you do the same.
抱歉 只是...
I'm sorry, it's just...
我们又得重新收集物资
We have to start the collection over.
要几个月后才能启程
It'll take months before we can leave.
要不我们去聚居地看看？
Why don't we check out the colony?
我们已经看够了
We've seen enough.
那里能有什么不同？
Why would this be any different?
我们可以找人做个伴
We could use the company.
也许那里的人不一样呢
Maybe these people are different.
阿比盖尔 哪里的人都一样
People are the same everywhere, Abigail.
无论是在北方、南方
No matter whether it's North, South,
还是某个破烂的船镇
or some shitty boat town.
尽管如此 我们也不能丢下他们不管
Still, we can't just leave them alone.
你以前说过 过去的人们
You said back in the old days,
都会互相帮助
people would help each other.
你说那是件好事
You said that was a good thing.
但是 世界上到处都是
And still, the world is full of the bodies
无私之人的尸体
of selfless people.
随便吧
Whatever.
我会给他们我的枪和一些弹药
I'm giving them my gun and some ammo
这样至少我能睡个好觉
so at least I can sleep well.
睡个好觉？
Sleep well?
你今天搞出这么大的乱子
How the fuck are you gonna sleep well
你他妈的还怎么能睡得着？
after the mess you made today?
你有没有想过
Did you even consider the fact
我们在矿井里差点就没命了？
that we nearly died at the mine?
但我们活下来了！
But we didn't!
这可不是你的功劳！
No thanks to you!
去你的 阿比盖尔
别自命清高了！
Fuck, Abigail. Get off your high horse!
下次你又会把我们带入险境 动动脑子
You'll get us into trouble again next time, just think.
行动之前动动你那该死的脑子
Fucking think before you act.
谢谢你今天的教训
Thanks for today's lesson.
真是太有用了
It was really useful.
我去放哨
I'll be on watch.
黑胡子一号 黑胡子一号
Blackbeard one, Blackbeard one.
这里是“旅馆老爹”五号 完毕
This is Papa Hotel five, over.
黑胡子一号 黑胡子一号
Blackbeard one, Blackbeard one.
这里是“旅馆老爹”五号 完毕
This is Papa Hotel five, over.
睡不着 嗯？
Can't sleep, huh?
我也睡不着
Me neither.
有点冷
It's chilly.
你在山谷里的表现太厉害了
That was really amazing back in the valley.
我是说 那些动作
I mean, those moves.
真的太厉害了
Really amazing.
那是运气
It was luck.
纯粹是运气
Sheer luck.
运气的问题在于 你最终会用完它
Problem of luck is that eventually you run out of it.
我不知道如果走投无路了 我该怎么办
I don't know what I would do if there was no way out.
很简单
It's easy.
我是认真问的
It was a serious question.
我也是认真回答的
So was the answer.
这个
This,
这是我的备用计划
this is my plan B.
上面还刻着我的名字
Even has my name on it.
真的吗？
Really?
假的
No.
不过 它是我的
Still, it's mine.
这是我的
Well this is mine.
嘿 这计划也不错
Hey, that's not a bad plan either.
嘿 伙计
Hey man.
哦 没事
Oh yeah, it's nothing.
我只是 扭伤了脚踝
I just, I twisted my ankle.
你知道 这不算什么
And you know, it's nothing compared
跟她经历的比起来
to what she's going through.
我知道她把发生的事都怪罪到自己身上
I know she blames herself for what happened.
她非常确信我们能到达聚居地
She was so convinced we get to the colony.
她说服了所有人
She convinced everyone else.
我只庆幸今天我们活下来了
I'm just glad that today we survived.
我们会帮你到达聚居地
We'll help you get to the colony.
该走了
Time to move on.
走吧
Come on.
我们必须休息一下
We must rest.
听着 如果我们停下来 我们就会死
Look, if we stop, we die.
我记得这个地方
I remember this place.
我以前经常和爸爸一起来这里
We used to come here a lot with my dad.
是吗？
Yeah?
几英里外有一个民用机场
There's a civil airport a couple of miles away.
我爸爸在那里有一架小飞机
My dad had a small plane there.
我们以前经常开着它到处飞
We used to fly it all the time.
哦 你觉得一架在那里放了
Oh, you think that some plane that's been lying around
好多年的飞机还能飞？
for years is gonna fly?
那里以前有几十架飞机
There used to be dozens of planes.
还有很多备件
Lots of spare parts.
我们可以试试
We could do it.
我们没时间浪费在这上面
We don't have time for this.
但是 我们也不能就这样走上几天
Still, we can't just walk for days.
听着 我知道镇上有一个地方
Look, I know a place in the town.
如果工具还在那里
If the tools are still there,
我们就能想出办法
we'll figure out something.
旧汽车、自行车 不管是什么 到时候再看
Old cars, bikes, whatever, we'll see.
以这个速度 我们要到日落才能到达
At this pace, we won't get there until sunset.
机场只有一个小时的步行路程
The airport is only about an hour's walk.
好吧
All right.
那就试试吧
Let's give it a try.
试试？
Give it a try?
听着 只有一条路通往机场
Look, there's one road to the airport.
如果我们在那里被包围 那就完了
If we get surrounded there, it's over.
到那时 步行将是我们最不需要担心的问题
Then walking will be the least of our problems.
嗯 这只是你的看法
Well, it's just your opinion.
我们投票吧
Let's have a vote.
谁赞成？
Who's for?
那就这么定了
It's decided then.
走吧 亲爱的
Come on, darling.
他们被枪杀了
They've been shot.
就在不久前
Not long ago.
进去看看
Check inside.
我们有两分钟时间
We've got two minutes.
只拿有用的东西
Take only what's useful.
我们必须吃点东西
We must eat something.
我们从早上到现在都没停过
We haven't stopped since this morning.
我们到机场再吃
We'll eat the airport.
为什么？
Why?
因为我们不是孤身一人
Because we're not alone.
抱歉
Sorry.
啊 也许不会弄死我们
Ah, might not kill us.
哦 咖啡
Oh, coffee.
我们得尝尝
We have to try it.
宾果！
Bingo!
对他们没什么用处了...
Not much use to them, so...
谢谢
Thanks.
很抱歉你们因为我们吵架了
I'm sorry you were arguing because of us.
哦 不关你们的事
Oh, it wasn't because of you.
给孩子起好名字了吗？
Do you have a name for the baby?
还没
Not yet.
但我不担心找不到名字
But I'm not afraid we won't find a name.
我害怕我的孩子将不得不孤独地成长
I fear that my child will have to grow up alone.
永远活在不确定中
Living in constant uncertainty.
我只希望有人能陪伴她 照顾她
I just want someone to be with her, to look after her.
我愿意为此付出生命
And I'd give my life for that.
看到了吗？
You see?
什么都没有
Nothing.
真不走运
That's unlucky.
要回头吗？
We should turn back?
不 绝对不能回头
No, no we shouldn't.
那他妈是最蠢的主意
That'd be a fucking stupid idea.
必须找到出路
We have to find a path.
好的 混蛋
Okay, asshole.
去你妈的
Fuck you.
够了
That's enough.
大卫 冷静
David, relax.
你他妈在干什么？
What the hell are you doing?
那原来是我爸的飞机库
Hey, that's where my dad's hangar used to be.
怎么打开？
How do we open it?
如果能修好 几小时就能到
If we can fix it, we can get there in a couple of hours.
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
飞机往哪里降落？
And where do we land the plane?
船到桥头自然直
We'll cross that bridge when we get there.
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
以防万一
Just in case.
好的
Okay.
我们四处看看 好吗？
We're gonna look around. Ok?
你没事吧？
You gonna be all right?
没事
Yeah.
如果是女孩叫贝儿 男孩叫本尼迪克特？
What do you say to,Belle or Benedict if it's a boy?
首先 肯定是男孩
First of all, it's definitely a boy.
其次 本尼迪克特
And secondly, Benedict.
听起来像吟游诗人之类的
Sounds like some kind of troubadour or something.
好吧
All right. Fine.
桑德拉和塞缪尔怎么样？
How about Sandra and Samuel?
该死
Dammit.
冷静大卫 你可以的 没事
Easy, David, you can do it, it's okay.
我他妈...
I can't fucking--
让我看看
Let me see.
没事的 坐下
It's okay, it's okay, sit back down.
没关系
It's all right.
让我看看
Let me see, come on.
天啊 你撞到了
My God, You hit it.
我要修好这破飞机
I'm gonna fix this shitty airplane.
带大家去船镇 好吗？
I'm gonna get us to the boat town, okay?
找到什么了吗？
Well, did you find anything?
没有
Nope.
他能修好对吧？
He can fix it, right?
你可是航空专家啊？
Well, you're the aviation expert, right?
我怎么知道？
How should I know?
真讨厌我总说中
Hate that I'm always right.
快走
Come on, let's move.
该死
Fucking hell.
快到了
Nearly there.
又怎么了？
What is it now?
不知道也不关心
I don't know and I don't care.
不 我知道
No, I know.
何时能起飞？
When can we take off?
飞机怎么还没好？
Why isn't the plane ready?
这可是飞机
It's a fucking airplane.
没事吧？
Are you okay?
只剩三分钟
No, we got three minutes.
三分钟后会怎样？
Wait, what happens in three minutes?
他们要来了
They're coming.
不 我们来不及了
No, no, no, we won't be ready.
他们来了
They're coming.
我不想死在这里 亲爱的
I don't wanna die here, honey.
快点
Please hurry up.
你早该先说这个
Yeah, you probably should have started with that.
也许 但现在都一样了
Maybe, but it's all the same now, isn't it?
60秒准备
60 seconds, be ready.
快走
Go, go, go.
有人会祷告吗？
Can anybody pray?
我们在天上的父啊
Our Father who liveth out there.
词说错了
Those are the wrong words.
快走！
Just go!
祷告没用！
It won't help!
快行动
Let's go, move it.
快点！
Come on!
太慢了
It's too slow.
会被追上
They're gonna catch this.
必须加速
We gotta go faster,
- 来不及了 - 我在努力！
- we're not gonna make it. - I'm trying!
他们追上来了
They're catching us.
找到了
Got 'em.
化油器
The carburetor.
红色按钮
The red button.
按！
Do it!
好了
Okay, that's it.
好了好了
All right, all right.
好险
That was close.
知道
I know.
天啊
Oh my God.
你做到了
You got it, you got it.
呼
Oh.
干得好 阿比盖尔
Well done, Abby.
真棒
Well done.
怎么回事？
Hey, what's happening?
控制不住了
I can't hold it.
什么？
What?
搞什么鬼？！
What the fuck?!
我不知道怎么办
I don't know what to do.
阿比盖尔 快降落
Abigail, you're gonna land this thing,
否则都得死
or we're all gonna die.
什么？
What?
那边 那边
Over there, over there.
好的好的
Okay, okay.
要坠毁了 准备防撞姿势
We're going down. Brace for impact, okay?
好
Okay.
没事吧？
You alright?
嗯
Yeah.
早说需要更多时间
Told you I needed more time.
好 抓住你
Okay, I gotcha.
好的
Okay.
好了 我们走吧
Okay, let's just go.
不 我们找个地方休息吃饭 好吗？
No, let's find somewhere to rest and eat, okay?
好吧 好吧
Okay, okay.
好的 好的 我们走吧
All right, all right, let's go.
真讨厌飞行
Fucking hate flying.
好了 新计划
All right, new plan.
我们到了
We're here.
河岸和聚居地
The riverbank and the colony
就在这些山的另一边
are on the other side of these hills.
我们两天内就能到达那里
Now we can get there in two days.
弹药？
Ammo?
嗯...
Um...
七发和八发？
Seven and eight?
好了 我们休息一下
Okay, let's get some rest.
天一亮我们就出发
We're leaving first light.
你还在生我的气吗？
Are you still mad at me?
我怎么能一直生你的气呢？
How can I stay mad at you?
好好睡吧 我的爱人
Sleep well, my love.
鸡肉
Chicken.
真好吃
Yum.
抱歉 我饿了
Sorry, I got hungry.
谢谢
Thank you.
太好吃了
So good.
等等
Wait.
小小的感谢
A little thank you.
你知道吗 你让我想起了我的妻子
You know, you remind me of my wife.
每当她有话要说时 她都藏不住
Whenever she had something to say, she could never hide it.
那些小皱纹在她嘴角跳动
Those little wrinkles dancing on the edge of her lips.
被发现了
Busted.
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
但你比我们更清楚什么对我们是正确的
But you know what's right for us better than we do.
我们互相依靠
We rely on each other.
即使我们帮助你 这一点也不会改变
That won't change, even if we help you.
她比你想象的要坚强
She's stronger than you think.
是的
Yeah.
不是因为这个
It's not about that.
那是什么？
What then?
我杀了她妈妈
I killed her mom.
还有她哥哥
And her brother.
我还能怎么弥补她呢？
How else could,I make it up to her?
除了照顾她
But to look after her.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我真的很抱歉
I really am.
但你也救了她
But you saved her as well.
这就够了
And that's enough.
在这个世界上 这就够了
In this world it is.
你知道吗 有个孩子
You know, there was this kid,
感染爆发三个月后
three months after the infection.
吉米
Jimmy.
他妈妈嗑药嗑得太嗨了
Now his mom had gotten so stoned
以至于当一个变种人
that she didn't even wake up when a feral
在剥她的皮时 她都没醒过来
was skinning her body.
我们救了他
We saved him.
他是个好孩子
He was a good kid.
一个聪明的孩子
A smart kid.
同时也是个厚脸皮的小淘气鬼
And a cheeky little rascal at the same time.
他从不听我的话
He never listened to me.
有一天 一个变种人把他的手指咬掉了
Well, one day a feral bit his finger clean off and
你知道当伤口没有
you know what happens when a wound doesn't
伤到动脉时会发生什么 对吧？
hit an artery, right?
需要几天时间才能完全变异
It takes days until you totally transform.
他是第一个
He was the first.
也是最后一个我看着经历这一切的人
And the last that I ever watched go through that.
我再也不会等待变异了
Never again did I wait for the transformation.
还有帕特里克
And there was Patrick,
和莎拉
and Sarah.
有时候你只需要逃跑
Sometimes you just gotta run
只顾自己就行了
and only worry about yourselves.
乔
Joe.
琳达
Linda.
那是我第一次看着有人死去
That was the first time I watched someone die.
为了不失去对方
Rather than lose the other.
杰西
Jess.
当她实在无法忍受的时候 她只是抓起一根绳子...
She simply grabbed a rope when she couldn't
然后...
take it any longer and...
有时候我觉得...
Sometimes I feel that...
我没有空间
I don't have the space
容纳我脑海中的所有面孔
for all the faces in my brain.
死亡
Dying.
死亡不算什么
Dying is nothing.
失去对你重要的人
Losing someone who is important to you.
那就不一样了
That's different.
是的 你知道有时候你不需要更多空间
Yeah, you know sometimes you just don't need more space.
有时候只需要放手
Sometimes it's just about letting them go.
你已经尽力了 卡西乌斯 我看得出来
You did everything you could, Cassius, I can tell.
是时候让她自己站起来了
It's time to let her stand on her own two feet.
别担心 你把她训练得很好
Don't worry, you trained her really well.
相信她就好
Just trust her.
她会一直在那里
She will always be there.
他们一直都在
They always are.
嘿 嗯...
Hey, um...
谢谢你的礼物
thanks for the gift.
现在 我们去睡觉吧 好吗？
Now, let's get some sleep, huh?
明天还有艰难的一天
Got a tough day tomorrow.
是的
Yeah.
这个地方被耕种过
This place has been farmed.
周围一定有人
Must be people around.
啊！
Ahh!
怎么了？
What is it?
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
天哪 你发烧了
Oh my God, you're burning up.
- 你还好吗？ - 我只需要休息一下
- Are you okay? - I just need some rest.
让我看看
Let me see.
我来帮你换绷带
Let me change your bandage.
别动 我没事
Stop, I'm alright.
对不起 对不起
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
别说他妈的一个字 蠢货
Don't say a fucking word, jackass.
你什么时候才打算说？
When were you gonna tell?
说什么？
Tell what?
我现在就该杀了你
I should kill you right here, right now.
给我一个我不该开枪打死你的好理由
Give me one good reason why I shouldn't shoot you right
就在这该死的时刻
this fucking second.
卡西乌斯 我们发现了一些东西
Cassius, we found something.
是啊 我也是
Yeah, me too.
来了
Coming.
振作起来
Pull yourself together.
想想你希望怎么死
Think about how you'd like to die.
至少现在你还有选择的余地
You have that choice for now.
你们是谁？想要什么？
Who are you and what do you want?
阿比盖尔 住手
Abigail, stop.
我们是和平的旅人
We are peaceful travelers.
只是需要稍作休息
We just need some rest.
这里没什么可拿的
There's nothing here to take.
阿比盖尔 嘿
Abigail, hey.
我叫阿比盖尔
My name is Abigail.
我们有个孕妇同行
We are travelers with a pregnant woman.
只需要一点帮助
We just need a little help.
好了 就站在那儿
All right, that's far enough.
我们需要药品...
We need medicine...
还有食物
and something to eat.
只要价格合理 我们可以付钱
We can even pay you if you ask a reasonable price.
好 把武器都放进箱子
All right, put all your weapons in the chest.
你也是
You too.
你们两个 到亮处来让我看清楚
You two, come up here where,I can see you in the light.
别耍花样 全部交出来
Uh-uh, all of them.
这样好多了 谢谢
That's better, thank you.
那就进来吧
Well, come on inside then.
这个...
Well...
呃...
Um...
欢迎来到我的...寒舍
welcome to my uh, humble abode.
老实说...
Oh gosh, needless to say,
如今很少有访客了
I rarely get visitors these days.
上次有人来是什么时候？
When was the last time?
天知道
God only knows.
你们有电
You have electricity.
是的
I do, yes.
电力有限 只够做研究
Not much, just enough for my research.
你是科学家？
You're some kind of scientist?
算是 我...
I am, I...
是工程师出身
graduated as an engineer.
以前和妻子一起做研究
Myself and my wife, we did our research together.
你妻子？
Your wife?
她在哪？
Huh, where is she?
好在书籍足够多
Fortunately, I have plenty of books.
我自学了房屋内部的所有系统
I've figured everything out for inside the house.
用地热发电供应热水
I have geothermal electricity, which provides hot water.
热水？
Hot water?
你们有热水？
You have hot water?
应有尽有 亲爱的
Oh, I have everything you need, my dear.
除了肉类
Except meat.
我现在不吃肉了
That I don't eat anymore,
但有自己的蔬菜水果园
but I have my own vegetables and fruit.
还有些面包
I even have some bread.
虽然干了点 但老式风味...
It's a little bit dry, but the old flavors, eh,
总让人怀念对吧？
you can't beat them, can you?
别太沉迷这些
Now don't get too used to it,
否则你们就舍不得走了
otherwise we won't be able to get rid of you, will I?
还等什么？
Well, what are you waiting for?
快请坐
Come on, take a seat.
久等了 请用
Sorry about the wait, here you go.
好的 谢谢
Yes, thank you.
祝胃口好
Bon appetit.
嘿
Hey.
还好吗？
You okay?
嗯
Yeah.
我时常问自己能坚持多久
And I just sometimes ask myself how I'm gonna hold out.
听着
Listen.
一切都会好起来的
Everything's gonna be just fine.
我害怕
I'm scared.
到这里之后 宝宝就不怎么动了
Since we've been here, I don't feel the baby moving.
相信我...
Trust me...
等到了目的地
Once we get there,
这小家伙就待不住了
you won't keep that big boy inside.
也可能是小姑娘
Or a big girl.
对 小姑娘
卡西乌斯
Cassius.
答应我 如果我出事
Promise me, if anything happens to me,
请照顾好她
you look after her, please.
我保证
I promise.
谢谢
Thank you.
干杯！
Cheers!
孕妇喝无酒精的
Well, non-alcoholic for the mother to be.
谢谢
Thank you.
其他人尝尝我自酿的惊喜
And a little homemade surprise for the rest of you.
这可是陈年佳酿
Oh, it's an excellent year.
我引以为豪
I'm very proud of it.
干杯！
Cheers!
嗯
Mm.
- 嗯- 干杯
- Mm. - Cheers.
- 干杯- 干杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.
你在这里住多久了？
So, uh, how long you been living here?
我？哦
Me? Oh,
二十多年了
over 20 years. Yes.
起初和妻子同住 现在...
First with my wife, and now, uh, well,
现在独自一人
now I'm on my own, yes.
你们呢？要去哪里？
And what about yourselves? Where are you headed to?
去聚居地
To the colony.
明智的选择我常通过无线电
Oh, brilliant idea. Yes, I speak to
和他们联系
them from time to time through my radio.
你怎么不去加入？
How come you're not with them?
你的知识对聚居地很有用
Surely your knowledge would come in handy at the colony.
承蒙夸奖 亲爱的
Oh, that's very kind of you, dear.
但我更适合独居
But I think,I'm better off here.
早在文明崩塌前
I mean, even before civilization, how shall I say,
我就不喜喧嚣
disappeared into the abyss.
从前去城市只为工作
Now, I was never impressed by crowded cities
那些浮华场所非我所好
and all that kind of ostentation.
真正的生活
I mean, we used to go there for work,
在远离尘嚣之处
but real life is here far away from all that.
深有同感
Yeah. Yeah, I hear you, buddy.
别误会
Yes, I mean, don't misunderstand me.
我对聚居地没有成见
I have no problem with the people at the colony.
相信现在那里建设得不错
And I am sure it's a very nice, cozy place these days.
我就是不明白那些时断时续的坚持
I just don't understand all that fitful adherence
对旧事物的盲目固守
to, you know, the old things.
灾难早就潜伏在秩序之下
I mean, there was chaos even before.
你说什么？
Excuse me?
别装傻 你明白我的意思
Oh, come on, you know what I mean.
这一切的根源？
How we got here?
七十多亿人口
Over seven billion people,
只顾着互相倾轧
all selfishly trying to one-up each other
对恶果视而不见
and not giving a shit about the consequences.
天啊 连基本的水粮供给都成问题
I mean, Christ, there wasn't even enough food and water.
可人类还是贪得无厌
But, oh, no, we all had to have another one of this
永不知足
and another one of that,
直到末日来临仍在苟延残喘
scrounging around until the end of days.
这场浩劫实属必然
I mean, what happened was necessary
但代价太过惨痛
Yeah, but it was still awful.
重点不在此处 亲爱的
Well, that's besides the point, my darling.
对病毒而言这可是天赐良机
It was heavenly for the virus.
至于我们人类
And as for us human beings, well,
不过是进化历程的必经阶段
it was just the next stage in our evolution.
必经阶段？
Next stage?
还不明白吗？
Don't you see?
适者得以生存
The strong have survived.
朋友们 唯有强者才配延续
And, my friends, only the strong should survive.
太残酷了
That sounds cruel.
不必为我忧心 个人见解而已
Oh, don't you worry about me. It's just my opinion.
无非是暴虐取代暴虐
I mean, one violent world replaced by another.
正如智人取代尼安德特人
The Neanderthal was overtaken by the homosapien.
进化从未停歇 现在也不会止步
Evolution didn't stop, and it's not going to stop now.
这怎能与进化相提并论？
How on earth can you compare this to evolution?
生命从不在乎主观意志 亲爱的
Life doesn't care about opinions, my dear.
尤其不会在意我们的
Especially not ours.
承认吧 这场天罚我们罪有应得
I mean, come on, we did deserve the punishment.
人类自诩万物灵长
We thought we were so superior,
实则不过是
but, I mean, a top predator
耗尽资源的顶级掠食者
that uses up all its own resources,
掠夺他者
preys on those of others,
终将走向灭亡
is destined for annihilation.
进化本就是修正过程
Evolution is always a correction.
血腥智人
Homo sapiens cruentus.
听你这番说辞 倒像是站在它们那边
Somehow I get the feeling that you're on their side.
我只是现实主义者
I am just a realist, my friend.
所有挣扎都是徒劳
I mean, all our attempts have been in vain.
我们无能为力
There is nothing we can do.
不出几代人
In a few generations, we won't
连凭吊这一切的文明都将湮灭
even be here to remember all of this.
顷刻间从文明倒退为野兽
Back to the instincts of the beasts,
所谓文明不过是脆弱的虚饰
from civilized naivety in a matter of moments,
转瞬
hours,
即逝
days.
这般苟活不如一死
I'd much rather die than live like this.
不 亲爱的 你不会的
Oh, no, you wouldn't, my dear.
好死终究不如赖活着
Living's always better than dying.
解药呢？
What about a cure?
总该有解药吧？
There could be one, right?
很遗憾 无药可解
No, unfortunately, there is none.
病毒入体的瞬间
The moment that virus enters your body,
就宣告了终结
it's over, finito.
不如直接爆头
Might as well just shoot
但何必呢？
yourself in the head, but why would you?
那根本不是活着
Because that's no life.
谁有资格判定？
And who decides?
生存本能才是终极驱动力
Even human beings only ever want to survive.
如此简单
So simple.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
我没事
Yeah, I'm okay.
不必担心这小子
Oh, don't you worry about him.
稍作休整就会恢复如初
He just needs a little rest and he'll be just fine.
这段小插曲
You won't even remember this little
很快就会被遗忘
inconvenience that I can promise you.
本想再请诸位喝一杯
I'd love to offer you all another drink,
可惜
but unfortunately,
时辰不多了
we haven't got much time left.
果然不出所料
Ah, I thought so.
知道这是什么吗？
Do you know what this is?
这是专门针对感染者的
Well, let's just say it's a special kind of dog whistle
特殊犬笛
that only works on the infected.
所以问题来了——
So my question is--
你们究竟是什么？
What are you?
嘿
Hey.
喂
这是哪？
Where are we?
你想干什么？
What do you want with us?
无线电频率
Radio frequency.
动机测试第十八组
Motivator test 18.
受试者四名旅人
Participants four travelers
两男两女
two male, two female.
其中一名孕妇
One of them is pregnant.
受试者状态
Condition of the subjects.
符合要求
Satisfactory.
喂
Hey.
怎么回事？
What's going on?
他们下药了
Drugged us.
请不要伤害我们
Please don't hurt us.
我们从未与你们为敌
We never cause you any harm.
现在说这些毫无意义
It doesn't matter now, my darling.
诸位另有使命
I've got plans for you.
什么使命？
What plans?
实验流程不可废
Even I can't skip the tests.
可知此为何物？
Now, who knows what this is?
这个腕带
This little wristlet
能发射感染者难以承受的
emits a sound frequency that the infected
特定声频
are unable to bear.
调整频率后 又能令其无法抗拒
Or if I change it, unable to resist.
无需藩篱 无需武器
I need no fence, nor do I need weapons.
自保足矣
I need no other protection.
你本可以拯救更多人
You could save others.
为何见死不救？
Why don't you help them?
既然我有其他计划 为什么要这么做？
Now, why would I want to do that when I've got other plans?
你真是疯了！
You really are crazy!
我知道你在想什么
I know what you think.
你觉得我是坏人
You think I'm the bad guy.
但我只是这个新世界的牧羊人
But I am merely the shepherd of this brand new world.
人类的时代已经结束了
The time of mankind has gone.
你这该死的混蛋
You bloody bastard.
哦对了 既然你问了
Oh, by the way, since you asked,
不想见见我妻子吗？
don't you want to meet my wife?
总之 我很想看看你的能耐
Anyway, I'm eager to find out what you're capable of.
尤其是你被咬过之后
Particularly because you've been bitten.
什么？
What?
不！
No!
这算什么？
Would you call this?
又一桩烂事
Another fuck up.
快走！
Come on, let's go!
阿比盖尔 拿车钥匙！
Abigail, get the car keys!
不！
No!
白痴！
You idiot!
住手！
Stop it!
你明知道他不能跟我们走！
Look, you knew damn well he can't come with us!
趁还能帮忙让我帮一把
Let me help, while I can.
给我个不宰了他的理由！
Tell me why I shouldn't fucking kill him!
因为这不该由我们决定
Because it's not up to us.
还没到那时候
现在我们得走了
Not yet. We gotta go.
怎么了？
What happened?
我羊水破了
My water just broke.
你打断我鼻子了
You broke my nose.
这算个屁啊？
Boo fucking hoo?
硬汉 这还算不上麻烦呢
That's the least of your problems, tough guy.
孩子要出生了
The baby's coming.
抓紧！
Hold on!
到了
There.
开灯
Lights.
是聚居地
The colony.
全体下车！
Everybody out!
我没弹药了！
I'm out of ammo!
走 我争取时间
Go, I'll buy you some time.
不 不要
No. No.
我会永远陪着你
I'll always be with you.
告诉儿子   我爱他好吗？
Tell that big boy I love him. Okay?
快走！
Come on!
喂！
Hey!
走！快走！
Go! Go!
跑啊！
Run!
快走！
Go!
醒醒
Wake up.
喂！
Hey!
嘿！
来人帮忙啊！
Hey, help!
我们该帮他们
We should help them.
安静
Quiet.
等着
Just wait.
喂！
Hey!
救命啊！
Hey, help!
嘘 你能行的
Shh, you can do this.
你可以的
You can do this.
躺下
Lie down.
呼吸！深呼吸！
Breathe! Breathe!
她需要休息
She needs to rest.
先离开这里
Leave her.
干得漂亮伙计
That was nice, man.
没被咬吧？
You didn't get bit, did you?
没有
No.
很好
All right.
还是要检查
We're still gonna check you.
随便查
Go ahead.
全干掉了？
Shoot them all?
当然
Sure did.
别担心
No worries, man.
你安全了
You're safe.
欢迎来到国王港
Welcome to the King's Harbor.
国王港？
The King's Harbor?
真他妈是个鬼地方
What a fucking shithole.
盯着他们
Keep an eye on them.
明白 老大
All right, boss.
我会的
I will do.
朋友你记住
You see, my friend,
活着总比死了强
living is always better.
（杀光变种人）
站住！
Stop!
就在那儿
Right there.
我是乔治 聚居地的负责人
My name's,George, head of the colony.
真高兴你们能来
I can't tell you how glad we are that you guys are here.
我们以为除了自己和那个疯科学家
We thought there was no one else alive except for us
世上没活人了
and that loony scientist.
你们从哪来？
Where are you from?
这位女士
The woman.
梅根来自远方的聚居地
Megan. She comes from a distant colony.
我们...我们一直在迁徙
And we've--we've been traveling.
明白
I see.
不必在意过去
Don't worry about your past.
有人担心你们带病毒来
Some folks here might be worried you brought some infection
或者半夜割他们喉咙
or that you'd cut their throats in their sleep.
但这不会发生   对吧？
But that's not true, right?
当然
No.
肯定不是
Of course it's not.
反正这儿也没东西可抢
Anyway, there's nothing here to be taken.
听说你们都干净
And I hear you guys are clean.
我个人非常欢迎
I am personally very happy for
多些帮手总归是好的
all the helping hands we can get.
先去休息吧
Now go get some rest.
今天够呛了
You've had a tough day.
你去哪？
Where are you going?
我想静静
I need some time on my own.
听着
Hey,
别乱跑
don't wander off.
天亮就出发
We're moving on. First light.
要是不想走呢？
What if I don't want to move on?
总是这样开头 阿比盖尔
It always starts like this, Abigail.
开始总是新鲜刺激
First, everything is exciting.
人人都很友善
Everyone is nice.
最后发现他们也不过是凡人
Then it turns out that they're also just humans.
那些男人看你的眼神不对劲
Listen, you saw the way the men were looking at you.
得了吧
Come on.
我能保护自己
I can protect myself.
但还是要走
Still, we're not staying.
就这么定了
That's it. Discussion is over.
定了？
It's over?
你又不是我爸！少命令我！
You're not my dad! Don't tell me what to do!
想留就留！
I'll stay if I want to.
好了好了
Hey, hey, hey.
过去这几天 我们多少次
The past couple of days, how many times
差点因你而丧命？
did we nearly die because of you, huh?
就因为你不听我劝告
Because you didn't listen to me.
我早说过
I told you.
独行更安全
We're better off alone.
是你独行更安全
You are better off alone.
你
You.
我不再是了
Not me anymore.
BB情况稳定
The baby's fine.
但这女人撑不住了
But the woman's not gonna make it.
她只剩几小时了
She's only got a couple of hours left.
她想和你谈谈
She wants to talk to you.
嘿！
Hey!
看看她
Look at her.
多漂亮啊
She's beautiful.
你好
Hello.
希望
Hope.
希望？
Hope?
这是她给我们生活带来的礼物
That's what she brought to our life.
我会看着她长大 成为坚强的女性
I'm going to see her grow up and become a strong woman.
但如果我做不到
But if I don't,
我需要你照顾她
I need you to look after her.
就像你照顾阿比盖尔那样
Just like you looked after Abigail.
我......
I--
求你了
Please.
我知道你信守了承诺
I know you kept your promise.
将她护送到了安全之地
And you brought her to safety.
我知道你会全力以赴
I know you'll do everything.
答应我
Just promise me.
你要教会她
You'll teach her
如何自立自强
how to stand on her feet.
求你了
Please.
我答应你
I promise.
请节哀顺变
I'm sorry for your loss.
能让我...
Can-can I?
呃
Um,
当然 当然
sure, sure.
我稍后就带她回来
I'll be back with her in a short while.
好吗？
Okay?
觉得来场老派复仇
So what do you think
这个主意怎么样？
about a little old fashioned revenge?
开战！
Fight!
喜欢吗？
You like it?
接下来要展示的
Well, then, what I'm going to show you
绝对让你大开眼界
will knock your socks off.
♪ 快来看看 现在就来瞧瞧 ♪
♪ Check it out, check it out now ♪
♪ 让所有男人都折腰 你早该知道 ♪
♪ Gonna make all the men bow,Yeah, don't ya know it ♪
♪ 尽情摇摆 尽情舞动 ♪
♪ Shake it up, shakeit up-- ♪
♪ 我们是幸运儿 ♪
♪ We are the lucky ones ♪
♪ 早已赢得胜利 ♪
♪ We have already won ♪
♪ 涂好指甲油 ♪
♪ Gonna paint our nails ♪
♪ 就要嗨翻全城 我们蓄势待发 ♪
♪ Then we'll paint this town,We're up for gettin' down ♪
♪ 听到我们的欢呼了吗 ♪
♪ Oh, can't ya hear us shoutin'? ♪
♪ 踩着高跟鞋 ♪
♪ With our high-heeled shoes ♪
♪ 穿着紧身裤 我们是舞会女王 ♪
♪ And our skinny jeans,We are the dancing queens ♪
♪ 乘着豪华轿车 ♪
♪ Riding in limousines ♪
♪ 没有什么能阻挡我们 ♪
♪ Ain't nothing gonna stop us now ♪
♪ 我们要让世界天翻地覆 ♪
♪ We'll turn this world right upside down ♪
♪ 没有什么能阻挡我们 ♪
♪ Ain't nothing gonna stop us now ♪
♪ 来吧女士们 这是专属我们的狂欢夜 ♪
♪ Come on ladies, this is girls' night out ♪
这不是个好主意
Wouldn't be a good idea.
怎么？那是什么？
Why? What is it?
是我们的保险措施
It's our little safeguard,
算是B计划吧
a plan B, if you will.
整个船镇都埋了炸药
The entire boat town is mined,
防止变种人入侵的最后手段
just in case, the ferrals ever did enter.
但你们也会同归于尽？
But then you'd die as well?
未必如此
Not necessarily.
这是什么？
What is it?
旧时代人们这里在修建大坝
Back in the old days, a huge dam was being built here,
所以河底挖了隧道
so they tunneled under the river.
大坝虽未完工 但隧道保留了下来
The dam was never completed, but the tunnel remained.
我们把它连通了船镇
And we've connected it to the boat town.
连通？
Connected?
有守卫吗？
Are there guards?
安全吗？
Is it safe?
当然安全
Sure it is.
另一头已经封闭
We've closed down the other end.
若遭袭击 我们可以撤离
If we're attacked, we can escape.
哇
Wow.
确实震撼
Wow it is.
你怎么想？
What do you think?
要和你父亲留下吗？
Are you and your dad going to stay with us?
不知道
Don't know.
而且他不是我父亲
And he's not my dad.
真的？
Really?
但他对你关怀备至
Seemed like he deeply cared for you.
这在末世可不常见
Quite an unusual thing around here.
早安 我的朋友
Good morning, my friend.
觅食节快乐
Happy hunger seek.
必须挡住他们
We've got to keep them back.
等等
Wait.
来不及了
It's too late.
带大家去隧道
Take the people down to the tunnel.
该验证你的B计划了
Let's see how your plan B works.
去找制高点
Go find a higher position.
你留下掩护
You stay here and cover them.
你呢？
And you?
我去找卡西乌斯
I'm going to go find Cassius.
快走！快！
Move! Move!
行动！
Move!
快撤离！
Move! Move!
嘿 等等！
Hey, hey, hey!
见过跟我来的女孩吗？
Have you seen the girl who came with me?
给我 我来抱
No, no, give her to me.
保护好她
Look, keep her safe.
我发誓做到
I will, I promise.
快撤 动作快！
Move, move, move, move!
没弹药了
I'm out.
妈的 我也是
Fuck, me too.
守不住了
We can't hold them.
全体撤离
Everyone escape.
走隧道
Use the tunnel.
去掩体
Go to the bunker.
老家伙你在哪？
Where are you, old man?
快离开这里
Let's get out of here.
谢谢
Thanks.
快走 动起来 动起来！
Go, move, move, move!
当心！
Look out!
趴下！
Down!
我们得走了
We've got to go.
这鬼地方要炸了
The whole shithole's ready to blow.
你到底想要什么？
What do you want from us?
你们就是不肯接受命运
You people just can't accept your fate,
走投无路的人最危险
and the desperate are dangerous.
我们很快会在更安全的世界团聚
We'll soon be together in a safer world.
不不不不
No, no, no, no.
嗷
Ow.
现在准备好了吗？
Are you ready now?
不！
No!
不！这不可能！
No! It can't be!
不！
No!
不！不要！
No! No!
去你的进化论
Fuck your evolution.
快动手啊伙计
Just do it, man.
（手链上文字：阿比盖尔）
阿比盖尔 快过来！
Abigail. Come on!
快走我们离开这！
Come on, let's go!
走！
Go!
快点阿比盖尔
Come on, Abigail.
动起来动起来
Move, move, move.
快快快
Go, go, go.
再等等
Not yet.
那个女孩还没出来
The girl hasn't come out yet.
好了
There.
五
Five,
四
four.
赶紧动手啊
Just do it, man.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
什么？
What?
没什么
It's nothing.
好的
OK.
放轻松
Take it easy.
明白吗？
All right?
别动
Don't move.
想都别想？
Don't even think about it?
- 好的 - 不许动
- OK. - Don't move.
明白
All right.
知道了
行吗？
OK?
放下武器好吗？
Just lower your weapon, OK?
那把剑
The sword.
- 放下武器 - 我没事
- Lower your weapon.-- - I'm fine.
好的
OK.
明白了
All right.
我们现在怎么办？
And what do we do now?
新家园在等着我们
A new home is waiting for us.
-= 翻译&校对&ASS特效：baki =-